I am applying for the Software Engineer position posted on LinkedIn. I have over 10 years of previous experience as a web developer on small teams and at start-up companies, which makes me a good candidate for this position.

As a Front-End Developer and Co-Founder at Redtail Design Co., I work closely with our designers, developers, and clients to build responsive websites, custom Wordpress templates and plug-ins from scratch. I was responsible for deploying web sites from conception to production. Most of my work was done using frameworks such as Wordpress and Angular. Our main clients are Ohio University, as well as the Ohio Brewers Association, and we work with many breweries around the state.

Before starting Redtail Design, I worked for Electronic Vision, where I started as an intern and moved on to do QA testing and bug fixing for software and websites. Eventually I was hired as a full time developer. In this position I built responsive websites from static design mockups using modern, semantic HTML, JS, and PHP. I frequently met with clients to discuss and determine the needs of their project. After finishing projects I trained clients on updating and managing their sites, as well as providing ongoing technical support and maintenance after project launch.

I was also the co-founder of a startup called LiveInteractive. Here we built a mobile app and webapp focused on being a digital billboard for local events. I led the webapp and advised the backend team, both made up of 2 other developers. The webapp was built using angular, with a custom "event poster creator" module built using the canvas API.

I believe my experience completing projects, delivering websites, and working directly with designers and clients will make me a great candidate for your software engineer position. Feel free to contact me with any questions about my qualifications.

Thank you for your consideration,
Sincerely,
Ben Weibel
weibel.b@gmail.com

740.541.0544

1375 NE Elk CT #150, Bend, OR 97701 Phone: 740.541.0544 Ben Weibel

weibel.b@gmail.com

10+ years experience, detail-oriented Front end Web Developer comfortable working on a small team. Skilled in working with designers and clients to translate their vision and needs into highly functional, beautiful web applications and websites.

# Experience

Aug 2016 - Present

#### FRONTEND DEVELOPER

#### Redtail Design Co. (Athens, OH)

- Build responsive websites and custom wordpress templates from scratch
- Deploy web sites from staging to production environment
- Create front-end interfaces with Angular
- Build custom REST APIs and Wordpress APIs for use with Angular Webapps

### Jan 2012 - Aug 2016 FRONTEND DEVELOPER

#### **Electronic Vision/Fitne Inc.** (Athens, OH)

- Worked closely with designers to build responsive websites from static design mockups using modern, semantic HTML, JS, PHP
- Met with clients to discuss and determine the needs of their project
- Did quality review and bug fixing for websites and software projects
- Maintained and provided ongoing technical support after project launch
- Trained clients on updating and managing their sites

#### Aug 2012 - May 2014 CO-FOUNDER / FULL STACK DEVELOPER

#### **LiveInteractive** (Athens, OH)

- Led a team of multiple developers
- Created webapp and hybrid mobile app (android)
- Built a REST API on AWS servers
- Met with potential investors and gave pitch presentations

#### 2006 - 2012

#### FREELANCE WEB DEVELOPER

- Met with clients to discuss and determine the needs of their project
- Designed, developed, and maintained websites
- Managed hosting and domain registration for clients
- Migrated old sites to new web hosts

Web Technologies & Frameworks: Wordpress, Angular, Node.js, Django, Bootstrap

# Technical Skills

Scripts & Languages: Javascript, Python, PHP, HTML, CSS/SCSS

Database: MySQL, MongoDB

Development Tools: NPM, Grunt/Gulp, Compass

Versioning: Git, Subversion

### Education

#### **OHIO UNIVERSITY**

2006 - 2012

Electrical Engineering, Computer Science Minor

192 credit hours completed

# References

**Tim Martin**, Owner, Redtail Design, Athens OH. phone: 740.590.3387 email: tim@redtaildesign.com

**Tony Presti**, COO, Fitne, inc, Athens OH. phone: 740.591.6297 email: tpresti@fitne.net

**Dan Krivicich**, Former CEO, Electronic Vision, Athens OH. phone: 740.591.1406 email: dkriv@ev.net

# Project Highlights

## Ohio Brew Week Beerfinder (ohiobrewweek.com/brews/)

AngularJS webapp pulling from a wordpress database using the REST API.

With over 300 individual beers to track from 46 different breweries being served at 42 separate participating venues, there were significant amounts of data to keep track of. Because of this we decided to use a simple wordpress backend interface that was already familiar to most of the Brew Week team. This allowed breweries and venues to manage their own individual pages, as well as input their own beer descriptions and information. Venues were then also able to mark which beers were no longer available, and have that information shared to the website and webapp in real time.

The webapp itself was built using AngularJS, and is fully responsive for mobile to desktop. LocalStorage was used to save a users tasting and wishlist data between visits.

Case Study: <a href="mailto:redtaildesign.com/project/ohio-brew-week/">redtaildesign.com/project/ohio-brew-week/</a>

# Marietta Ohio CVB map (mariettaohio.org/map/)

Google map build that pulls in information from a wordpress data using the REST API.

The Visitors Bureau for Marietta had a small team, with a large number of businesses to work with, so we wanted to streamline the process as much as possible, and limit the amount of training needed to update data throughout the site. I used a similar method to the Ohio Brew Week Beerfinder by pulling data from the wordpress posts they already made into a google map. This allowed them to update information and images in one spot. Location data was also added to the businesses' wordpress post data, which generates a pin on the map. Basic filters were added to the map to allow a user to choose what they want to see.

Case Study: redtaildesign.com/project/marietta-washington-county-cvb/

More portfolio projects available by request and viewed at <u>redtaildesign.com/projects</u>.